CHRISTINE SCHATZ

CONTACT

www.christineschatz.com

**** 323-828-8487

Q Los Angeles, CA

in /christineschatz

ChristineSchatz

SUMMARY

I truly enjoy problem solving. Whether it's figuring out how an app's data should be structured or how a user experience should be designed, I'm energized by crafting creative solutions to problems. I'm drawn to good people who enjoy sharing ideas and making a difference.

EDUCATION

Penn State University Sept. 2018 - Current MPS Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

Northampton Community College

A.S. Computer Science 2015

Dean's List, GPA: 3.9

University of California, San Diego

B.A. Visual Arts: Media 2008 Graduated with Honors

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, JavaScript, Java, PHP, Scala FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES: Rails, Laravel

TESTING: RSpec, Capybara

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, jQuery, React,

Riot, Vue

METHODOLOGIES: Object-oriented design,

DATABASE: ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQL

DEVOPS: Docker, Vagrant

ACTIVITIES

The Loop Founder & Writer

Music blogger for popular, Hype-Machine ranked music blog "The Loop." I work with PR agents and artists to feature independent music. I'm also a music reviewer for Fluence.io

Coders > Cancer Hackathon Developer

Collaborated on a team of 4 to develop Ladybug, a text messaging system that reminds women to do their monthly self breast exam. Used Ruby on Rails and HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to design the splash page

EMPLOYMENT

Programmer/Analyst II

Remote Penn State University Apr. 2017 - Current

• Used Ruby on Rails, Vue.js, Angular, and jQuery to build and improve various ed tech applications

- Built a Ruby on Rails application that will be used by faculty across Big Ten universities
- Worked with faculty members in development process, from prototype to deliverable
- Fixed bugs and improved existing applications

Junior Full Stack Engineer

New York, NY lan. 2016 - Apr. 2017

• Used JavaScript, riot.js, jQuery to implement new features on pet retail website

- Used PHP (Laravel) on the backend
- Fixed bugs
- · Refactored and cleaned up parts of a large legacy codebase

Junior Developer (Contract)

ValuePenguin

New York, NY Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Built interactive tools such as a credit card calculator using React
- Wrote Scala and PHP to customize data on the back end
- Developed in Docker containers

PROJECTS

the <hive>

A social networking site for software developers looking to collaborate on a side project. Users can coordinate meetups using an in-app messaging system. Users can also search for a project by any given city or zip code.

- Played a large role in implementing the Google Geocoding API to render location results.
- Designed the splash page
- Built a portion of the CRUD features for projects
- Implemented AJAX for smoother data loading

Stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, ¡Query, AJAX, Materialize, Sass

URL: https://code-hive.herokuapp.com

Emotional Baggage Check iOS app

The iOS app version of the popular desktop site Emotional Baggage Check. Users can post "baggage" anonymously as well as receive an anonymous response.

- Used Swift and Parse API as a backend
- Utilized MVC design pattern, divide and conquer strategies, and debugging tools throughout development

Stack: Swift, Objective-C, Parse

AWARDS

Style of Sound · Best Music Blog Award

Oct. 2014

Awarded ranking in Style of Sound's "Most Influential Music Blogs of 2014" list